# KYLE CANO

Corpus Christi, TX, US · +1 (920) 350-9366

dw951012@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-cano/

Experienced in web development with over 9 years of experience. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

Enthusiastic project manager, eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Clear understanding of the requirements and implemented the idea as reality. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in new skills.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**DEC 2020 - FEB 2022** 

## **FULL STACK ENGINEER**

## WANDER · CONTRACT

JavaScript, React, Angular, AWS, NFT platform

- \* Built React Drag-Resize-Rotate extension component with pure JavaScript and updated features.
- \* Built ERC-721(NFT tokens), ERC-20, BEP-20 tokens and packaged the tokens to website with react.js-typescript
- \* Created safe deflationary tokens on ethereum blockchain and binance smartchain network with solidity(these tokens are supported by all popular wallets like Trust, Metamask, Math, TokenPocket, Safepal, etc.).
- \* Migrated the frontend Angular version from AngularJS to Angular latest version(12) and updated the platform design

### **APR 2018 - OCT 2021**

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

## APOLLOFACTOR · CONTRACT

Angular, React(Next), Ionic, Deno framework, R Language

- \* Company Market Range analysis and estimate by R Language
- \* Built the PDF market report service with deno framework
- \* Design both of Angular developer and React client portals and firebase connection
- \* Maizzle email service and running the system with dockerbucket, MySql RDS db and load balancer

# MAY 2016 - APR 2018

## **SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER**

## SKYKICK · CONTRACT

MERN stack, AWS

- \* Building a BSC token platform by means of Bitquery graphql: Getting all token information(name, simbol, address, dex price, market cap, holders, volume), 4 minutes delay for the whole tokens.
- \* Built a main platform with Node and React from scratch including Database Design
- \* react-redux, redux-sagas state management

- \* Pubnub chat api, Zoom Api Integration
- \* Multi ternant by one source code and subdomain CMS system- Pubnub chat api, Zoom Api Integration

**JUL 2015 – APR 2016** 

### **FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER**

## FREELANCEER.COM · FREELANCE

- \* Designed and developed new trading strategies to establish and hedge positions in real-time, buying and selling delta1 products(index, options, futures, ETFs, etc), stocks, FX derivatives and related products.
- \* Rich experience in Node Express js, Sails, and Nestjs: implementing JWT authentication system, rest api service, socket io connection, sequelize npm MVC backend structure and firebase connection
- \* Built an admin management system with Angular 8 and node js from basic mockup design using AWS EC2 instance and RDS database, and GCP gtag was integrated. RxJS and angular pure modules were used
- \* Youtube & Vimeo API, Paypal & Stripe payment api integration and managing the whole projects by Github
- \* Updated the server security with AWS and token based node application
- \* AuthO platform and JavaScript SDK were used for the user authentication

**MAY 2013 - JUN 2015** 

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

WEB MAVENS · FULL TIME

# **EDUCATION**

2009 - 2013

**SAN BEDA UNIVERSITY** 

**BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING** 

# **SKILLS**

- Html/CSS
- JavaScript & TypeScript
- R Language
- PHP
- Solidity
- UI/UX Design
- Database Architecture
- Server Management
- Project Management

- Teamwork
- Creativity
- Problem Solving
- Decision making
- Stress Management
- Confidence
- Self-motivated
- Humor